A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1978-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1978-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.811
This collection consists of 10,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 1981 September 1.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general and administrative committee files.
Organization
Series I: General Records, 1978-1979, Boxes 1-24
Series II: Administrative Committees, 1978-1979, Boxes 24-25
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Adams Papers 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Law 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Medical 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Affairs 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association--General 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Women 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report--President's 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Anthropology 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Position 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Art--General 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Art--Bayly Museum 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Asian Studies 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities (3 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Association of Western Universities 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--ACC 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--CFA 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--Finances 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--General (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--NCAA1978-1979......Athletics--Personnel 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Attorney General--State 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Auditor--Internal 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - "Ba-Bm" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - "Bn-Bz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Biology 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Business and Auxiliary Service 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Business and Finance 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - "Ca-Ck" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - "Cl-Cz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Cavalier Daily 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Civil Rights 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Classics 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Clinch Valley College--General 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - College Entrance Exam Board 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Commerce 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Community College 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Comptroller--State 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Comptroller--University 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Computer Activities (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Consortia--Central Virginia 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--General 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia (3 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Tidewater 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Valley 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Consortia--Western 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Continuing Education 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Council of Presidents 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - "Da-De" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - "Df-Dz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Danforth Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Darden Business Sponsors 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Darden School 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Dean's Meetings 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Development--General 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Drama 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - "E-Ev" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - "Ew-Ez" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Economics--Jefferson Center for Political Economy 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Education 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Energy--Federal 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Energy--State 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Engineering and Buildings (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Engineering--Research Laboratory for Engineering Sciences (RLES) 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - English 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Enrollment 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Environmental Sciences 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Equal Opportunity Programs 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Faculty--General 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Fitzgerald Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Food Services 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Food Services--ESAB Building 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Ford Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - French Literature 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - "Ga-Gl" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - "Go-Gz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - General Assembly--Legislation 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - General Assembly--House Appropriations 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - German 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Gifts and Grants "A-B" 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Gifts and Grants "C-E" 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Gifts and Grants "F-H" 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Gifts and Grants "I-M" 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Gifts and Grants "N-Sl" 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Gifts and Grants "Sm-Z" 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Governor's Office--Administration and Finance 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Governor's Office--Education (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Governor's Office--General 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Governor's Office--Transportation and General Safety 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Health, Education and Welfare 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Hereford, Frank L. Jr. 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Higher Education of 1965 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Higher Education--Title I 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Higher Education--Title IV 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Higher Education--Title IX 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Highway Department 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - History 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Honor System and Committee 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Housing 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Institute of Government 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Institutional Analysis 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - International Students 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Law Center for Oceans Law and Policy 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Law--General 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Law School Foundation Report 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Lawn Society 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Legal--General 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Library--General 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Madison House 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Mariners Museum 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Mathematics 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Medical Center--Current Operations 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Medical Center--General (4 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--General 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Medical Center--Hospital Monthly Statistic Reports 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Medical Center--Personnel 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee, Faculty Meeting and Executive Committee 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Medical School--General 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Medical School--Nursing--General 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Mental Health and Mental Retardation 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Music 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - "Na" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - "Ne-Nz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - NASA 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC) (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--Advancement of Public Negro Colleges 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--F.Y.I. 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - National Science Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Newcomb Hall 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - "Pi-Pz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Parking and Transit 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Personnel--Employee Relations 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Personnel--General 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Personnel and Training 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Philosophy 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Physics 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Planning--Physical 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Lawn Colonnades 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Rotunda Forecourt 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Rotunda Glass Doors 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Ruffner Hall 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Shannon Court 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning--University Projects: Status Reports 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Budget--Capital Outlay 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Budget--State (2 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Budget--University of Virginia 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Promotions 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Property Records and Insurance 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Provost for University 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Associate Provost for Research 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Psychology 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Purchase and Supply 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Purchasing 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - Recommendations A-Z 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - Registrar 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - Religious Studies 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - ROTC--General 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - ROTC--Army 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - ROTC--Navy 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - "Sa-Sl" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - "Sm-So" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - "Sp-Sz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 19)
  - Senate--University 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Space and Energy Management 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Speeches--Current 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - Sponsored Programs 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE) (4 folders) 1978-1979 (Box 20)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE) 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--Mission Explication 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--Council Notes 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - State Department of Education 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - State Farm 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - State Fire Marshal 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - Student Affairs 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - Student Affairs 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - Student Council 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - Student Council Minutes 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - Summer Session 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - Travel Invoices 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - Treasurer 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 22)
  - United States Savings Bonds 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - United Way 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - University Guides 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - University Police 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - University Press of Virginia 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - University Relations 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - University Research Association 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - University Union 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - "Va-Vir" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - "Vir-Vz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 24)
- Series II: Administrative Committees
  - Admissions 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Afro-American Affairs Advisory 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Algernon Sydeny Sullivan Award 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Arboretum 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Architectural Advisory 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Archives and Records Advisory 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Athletic Advisory 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Bayly Museum 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Calendar 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Catalogue 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Cemetery 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Chapel 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Commencement and Convocation 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Commencement and Convocation--Subcommittee--Processions 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Commencement and Convocation--Subcommittee--Public Occasions 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Community Colleges 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Computers 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Danforth Fellowships 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Development Steering 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Educational and Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Energy Conservation 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Fraternities and Sororities 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Fulbright Grants 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Graduate Opportunities 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Graphics 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Gwathmey Award 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Housing 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - International Students 1978-1979 (Box 24)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Lectures--Page, Barbour, and Richard 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Lectures--Special 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Library 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Master Plan 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Minority Student Affairs Advisory Council 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Names 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Patents 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Radiation Safety 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Registration 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Rhodes Scholarship 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - ROTC 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Scheduling 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Scholarships, Grants-in-Aid, Employment, and Loans 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Subcommittee--Laser Safety Disposal Hazardous Materials 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Security and General Safety 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Student Activities 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Student Health 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Student Rights and Responsibilities 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Summer Grants 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Summer Sessions 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Teacher Education 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Traffic Appeals 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Traffic and Parking 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - University Committee on Students 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - University Press 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - University Union 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Status of University Students 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Ad Hoc--Water Conservation 1978-1979 (Box 25)